Rebel Soldier Hustler Prisoner Fugitive Firebrand
Young Winston is a action, adventure, drama film
directed by Richard Attenborough.
This historical drama is an account of the early life of British politician Winston Churchill, including his childhood
years, his time as a war correspondent in Africa, and culminating with his first election to Parliament.
Winston Churchill, played by Simon Ward.
Le capitaine du 35e Sikhs, played by Peter Cellier.
Lord Randolph Churchill, played by Robert Shaw.
Lady Jennie Churchill, played by Anne Bancroft.
Mr. Welldon, played by Jack Hawkins.
George E. Buckle, played by Ian Holm.
Young Winston is a 1972 British epic biographical adventure drama war film in Panavision covering the early years
of British Prime Minister Winston Churchill, based in particular on his 1930 book, My Early Life.
The first part of the film covers Churchill's unhappy
schooldays, up to the death of his father.
The second half covers his service as a cavalry officer in India and the Sudan, during which he takes part in the cavalry charge at Omdurman, his
experiences as a war correspondent in the Second Boer War, during which he is captured and escapes, and his election to Parliament at the age of 26.
Churchill was played by Simon Ward, and the cast included Robert Shaw (as Lord Randolph Churchill), John Mills (as Lord
Kitchener), Anthony Hopkins (as David Lloyd George)  and Anne Bancroft as Churchill's mother Jennie.
Other actors included Patrick Magee, Robert Hardy, Ian
Holm, Edward Woodward and Jack Hawkins.
The film was written and produced by Carl Foreman
and directed by Richard Attenborough.
It was nominated for three Academy Awards: Best
Screenplay, Best Art Direction (Donald M.
Ashton, Geoffrey Drake, John Graysmark, William
Hutchinson, Peter James) and Best Costume Design.
Young Winston was released to cinemas on July 28, 1972.
The film explores themes of parliament, election, british
politics, turn of the century, 19th century.
The tone is emotional.